<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epstein Financial Video Blog</title>
    <description>We create greater clarity, confidence and the capabilities for entrepreneurs, medical practitioners, 401k participants and retirees to maximize the power of their financial future. Our goal is to help you generate a &quot;paycheck for life&quot; to pay for all the things you desire to do and to live a fulfilling and engaged life.</description>
    <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 15:59:32 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 15:59:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can Your Employees Make the Most Out of Social Security?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jsOVTUs96Xg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can your employees maximize the benefits of social security and use it to its full advantages?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, the Obama administration made some major cuts to social security. Let me be clear—the social security trust fund has no money in it. It’s a ponzi scheme. Some people pay in, but far more people pay out. Every administration for the last 25 years has tried cutting off various loopholes and raising taxes to shore up the system, but it just hasn’t happened. What the Obama administration did was eliminate some of those loopholes that would’ve allowed you or your spouse to maximize this benefit. And today, those are all gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news, however, is that they’ve made it easier for you and your employees to calculate your benefits. What do you and your employees need to know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you should &lt;strong&gt;go to the social security website &lt;a href=&quot;www.ssa.gov&quot;&gt;www.ssa.gov&lt;/a&gt;, log in, enter your personal information, create an ID, and generate your social security report.&lt;/strong&gt;Once you do that, the report is going to tell you what you’re going to get for income at age 62, what you’re going to get at 66, and what you’ll get if you wait until 70, which is the age that guarantees the largest benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When should you take your social security? That depends on a lot of factors, primarily the** state of your health, whether or not you like working, and whether or not you have other savings or investments in play.**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, I’ll tell you about of a client of mine, Jim, who was facing the same scenario. Jim retired two years ago, and we set up a strategy for him to determine when he should take his social security and how he should spend down his other assets. Jim has money in cash, money in a Roth IRA, and money in his 401(k). Not only that, but his retired wife is receiving a monthly pension and taking her own social security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim is 63 years old now. The first strategy I shared with him was, once he retired, to live on as much money that’s already been taxed so that he could live tax-free. What Jim is doing is spending down his cash first and paying absolutely nothing in taxes. When he turns 66 and a half, he’s going to start taking his social security. From there until age 70 and a half, he’s going to pay nothing in taxes because he’s living off his cash (which he’s already paid taxes on), his social security payment will be tax free, and he has money in his Roth IRA which he can draw down and not pay any tax on. At age 70 and a half, he’s going to have to start taking money out of his 401(k) and his IRAs, but he’s going to take out his minimum distribution, and by doing that, he’ll pay as little in tax as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you might be saying, “Charlie, I don’t want to wait until I’m 66 and a half or 70 to collect my social security. I had a father who worked his whole life, stop working, die the next month, and then never collect a dime from social security.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s an important consideration. Just bear in mind, if you start taking social security at 62, and you’re still working, you’re going to pay taxes on your social security benefit. Basically, for every dollar you earn, you’re going to pay 30%, 40%, or even 50% of tax money on that money while you’re working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=When you should start taking your social security depends on many factors.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/how-can-your-employees-make-the-most-out-of-social-security.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“When you should start taking your social security depends on many factors.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I know there are still a lot of people who want to get their money as soon as possible. What’s the best solution for them? Again, it depends on how much you have in savings, what you have in your 401(k), how much you have in a Roth account, and other factors. Do you have a history of health and longevity in your family? Psychologically, can you wait to take your social security benefit? Every year that you wait, you’re going to earn an 8% return on that benefit. In other words, that monthly income is going to grow by 8%. That’s a guaranteed return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I know there are also some of you out there saying there’s no money in the social security system and wondering what happens if they take it away. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re 55 or older, you can count on social security to be there.&lt;/strong&gt;If you’re 50 or under, depending on how much money you do have at retirement some day, I think they’re going to means test social security. What that means is if you make too much income from your investments, you’re not going to receive any of your social security or a reduced benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me when I say that this is how it’s going to have to happen. As it is now, there are too few people paying into a system and too many taking out of it. There hasn’t been any president yet that has had enough political clout to take on social security, and more specifically, to take on congress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;strong&gt;either take it at 62, take it at 66 and a half, or wait until 70 to get the largest benefit.&lt;/strong&gt;Make sure you have your employees go online and check their social security statement and verify that they’ve received all their credits for their income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to schedule a meeting for your employees where we can help them analyze their social security and their options, we’d be delighted to do so. All you have to do is send me an email and we’d be happy to set up an appointment. Stay tuned for my next video, where I will cover some strategies you can use at no cost to help your employees create that paycheck for life and be even more successful than they are today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/how-can-your-employees-make-the-most-out-of-social-security.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/how-can-your-employees-make-the-most-out-of-social-security.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Would Simpler Bank Regulations Mean for You?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CW1toVxbpdc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Would Simpler Bank Regulations Mean for You?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently a guest on Fox Business’s show “Countdown to the Closing Bell with Liz Claman” where I talked about the prospect of simpler banking regulations under the Trump administration. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s a quick summary of what I talked about.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump has rolled back the Dodd-Frank Act, which restricted the ability of many small banks to make loans to small business owners.  Back in 2007, as an original founder and trustee of a community bank in Massachusetts, NuVo Bank, now know as Merchants Bank, the Dodd-Frank Act strangled our ability to loan money to small businesses. &lt;strong&gt;Small businesses make up 80% of this economy, and now they will be able to access capital much easier.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s good for jobs and growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When small banks were held to the same standards as the big banks, it didn’t work. However, does this mean all of the Dodd-Frank Act should be torched?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With President Trump’s first action, Congress will have to get involved and trim down the Dodd-Frank Act. However, the biggest piece to be trimmed is the bureaucracy. &lt;strong&gt;The notion that more regulation will prevent things from happening is wrong.&lt;/strong&gt;The free markets need to be free and the free markets will determine what’s in the best interest of businesses and consumers. When the smaller banks are able to release that capital to smaller businesses, the results will be exponential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Small businesses make up 80% of this economy%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/what-would-simpler-bank-regulations-mean-for-you.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“Small businesses make up 80% of this economy”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To catch my full appearance, just click play on the video above. Thank you for watching.  Let me know your views on this topic.  Just send me your email at &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(99,100,101,112,115,116,101,105,110,64,116,104,101,52,48,49,107,99,111,97,99,104,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;cdepstein@the401kcoach.com&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/what-would-simpler-bank-regulations-mean-for-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/what-would-simpler-bank-regulations-mean-for-you.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Help Your Employees Save for Retirement?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FWCYOaAGPcQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.scheduleonce.com/Consultation-EpsteinFinancial&quot;&gt;Schedule a Consultation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epsteinfinancial.com/free-book-offer.html&quot;&gt;Click here to get your free book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I’ll cover how much your employees, on average, will need to save to create their paycheck for life for retirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I’ll move on to something called the “Rule of 72,” which is a shortcut for figuring out how fast your money grows and how fast inflation can reduce the purchasing power of that paycheck for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, I like to tell employees that &lt;strong&gt;they need to save at least 10% of their pay,  year in and year out, to effectively accumulate enough money to create a paycheck for life.&lt;/strong&gt; More importantly, your employees need to calculate how much of their current income they need to replace when they get to retirement in order to successfully replace their income and have that paycheck for life. This is a calculation we’ve found that most employees don’t bother with, which is unfortunate because it’s the most important number. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is this calculation done? In my industry, we have a technical word for it called the &lt;strong&gt;“income replacement ratio,” or the “income replacement formula.” &lt;/strong&gt;It works like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On average, when you reach retirement age, you’re probably not going to need 100% of your income; you’ll probably only need 70%, 80% or 90% of it. Why? Let’s imagine that you’re 40 years old, your annual income is $50,000, and you decide you want to retire at age 66 and start collecting that paycheck for life. We’ll also assume that you’re going to get social security, which will make up for a portion of that income replacement. If you’re only going to need 80% of your income, that would equate to $40,000. That’s $40,000 in today’s dollars, but complicating matters is this little problem called inflation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economic definition of inflation, in layman’s terms, is too much money chasing too few goods. Inflation basically erodes your purchasing power over the years, so you need your income or your savings to grow in order to keep up with the cost of living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t let your employees retire without a paycheck for life.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/how-can-you-help-your-employees-save-for-retirement.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“Don’t let your employees retire without a paycheck for life.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the Rule of 72 comes into play. &lt;strong&gt;The Rule of 72 is a shortcut to figuring out how fast your money is going to be eroded by inflation.&lt;/strong&gt; The rule of 72 helps you figure out how long you have until your income erodes to half of what you are currently making. So, since the inflation rates is 3%, you’ll take 72 and divide it by three. If the inflation rate was 4% and 5%, you would divide 72 by four or five. 72 divided by three is 24, therefore it would take 24 years for a $50,000 income to erode to $25,000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s turn this calculation around under the same assumption of working until age 66 with an annual income of $50,000. Replacing 80% of that $50,000 would equate to $40,000. However, in 24 years, that $40,000 is only going to be worth $20,000. That means you would actually need $80,000 just to keep pace with inflation when you get into your mid-60s. 
&lt;br /&gt;If you’re thinking that this sounds too complicated or you’re wondering how your employees are going to calculate this, I have good news. &lt;strong&gt;Most 401(k) record keepers have calculators that will help your employees calculate their income replacement ratio and the effects of inflation. &lt;/strong&gt;As a matter of fact, there are even some record keepers who, instead of giving out a statement of a lump-sum amount of how much money your participant has accumulated in their plan, they’ll actually convert that amount to a monthly income at the participant’s retirement age. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if somebody needs $2,000 a month to live on and they have only $1,350 projected, the calculator will notify them that they’re short $650 and inform them how much additional money they would need to save at a reasonable rate of return at 3% inflation in order to create that paycheck for life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like a list of the record keepers that actually do those calculations or convert the lump sum amount that they’ve saved into a monthly amount, email me at &lt;a href=&quot;javascript:void(location.href='mailto:'+String.fromCharCode(99,100,101,112,115,116,101,105,110,64,101,112,115,116,101,105,110,102,115,46,99,111,109))&quot;&gt;cdepstein@epsteinfs.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re covering here is mission critical. If your employees don’t know how much income they need to replace, what inflation will do to their paycheck over time, and what they need to save, they’re going to end up without enough money in their retirement account to create that paycheck for life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way we can help your employees understand exactly how much they need to save is something called a &lt;strong&gt;“gap statement.”&lt;/strong&gt; The gap statement simply performs this calculation for them. As a matter of fact, with all our clients, we create a gap statement for all their employees. If you’d like a sample copy of our gap statement, feel free to email me again at the aforementioned address. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about this topic and you would like to connect with me, don’t hesitate, send me an email. I look forward to helping you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/how-can-you-help-your-employees-save-for-retirement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/how-can-you-help-your-employees-save-for-retirement.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Join Me and Listen in on Christmas Eve</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/wmbs-charlie-epstein---x----608-458x---.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
I’ve got some exciting news to share. This Saturday, December 24th, I am going to be a guest on The Western Mass Business Show with Ira Bryck. We are going to talk about how an “engaged purpose” drives everything that happens at Epstein Financial Services. We’ll also talk about how we bring light to all the things that need improvements for owners, employees, and customers. We hope you’ll join us on Saturday at 11 a.m. on WHMP AM 1400.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/join-me-and-listen-in-on-christmas-eve.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/join-me-and-listen-in-on-christmas-eve.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Your New 401K Resource</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_q7on4S_DDo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epsteinfinancial.com/contact.html&quot;&gt;Schedule a Consultation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epsteinfinancial.com/free-book-offer.html&quot;&gt;Click here to get your free book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture this: you’re getting ready to go on a great vacation. You’re standing at the airport gate when all of a sudden, the agent comes on the intercom and says, “The captain would like me to announce that there is an 85% chance that this flight will not make it to your vacation destination on time and safely. Have a nice trip!” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you going to get on that plane? Of course not! Why? Because there is a significant chance that you won’t make it there safely or on time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my 36 years as America’s 401K Coach, I’ve learned that there is an 85% chance that 85% of your employees in your retirement plan will not get to their destination—retirement—on time and safely. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why I’m starting this video blog. I will share all of the secrets to creating a successful retirement plan with you. You can even click here to get a free copy of my book, Save America, Save! so that you can learn all of my secrets right away. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I can help you create a paycheck for life.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/your-new-401k-resource.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“I can help you create a paycheck for life.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of the next year, I’ll send you a series of videos talking about everything that you can do as a plan sponsor to help your employees create their own paychecks for life. In fact, my first book, Paychecks for Life, has sold more than 20,000 copies. I highly recommend that plan sponsors read it so that you can pass valuable information on to your employees; click here if you are interested. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every two weeks, you will get a video featuring one of my secret recipes. For example, you’ll learn how to reverse engineer the expenses for your retirement plan. You can reduce them or get Uncle Sam to pay 30% to 40% of those expenses. I’ll also discuss automatic features, part of the Pension Protection Act that provides complete fiduciary protection for you as a plan sponsor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take advantage of these powerful tools, you will help your employees save enough money to create that paycheck for life. If you have any specific questions, give me a call or send me an email and I’ll answer you with a video. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/your-new-401k-resource.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/your-new-401k-resource.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
