<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epstein Financial Video Blog</title>
    <description>We create greater clarity, confidence and the capabilities for entrepreneurs, medical practitioners, 401k participants and retirees to maximize the power of their financial future. Our goal is to help you generate a &quot;paycheck for life&quot; to pay for all the things you desire to do and to live a fulfilling and engaged life.</description>
    <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 16:48:32 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 16:48:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Truly Fulfilling Your Duties as a Retirement Plan Sponsor?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yxZEzlsV2fo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of activity right now in the 401(k) industry, but today I want to talk specifically about a court case that has been dragging out for the past six or seven years: Tibble v. Edison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the judge finally ruled that if you have a 401(k) plan, you’ve got a duty of prudence and loyalty to your participants. You must make sure to monitor your investment plans. With the correct process in place, you should be able to prudently choose investment for your employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, which was over a $3 million plan, the sponsors’ fiduciaries had both institutional share mutual funds and retail share mutual funds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, what’s the difference between these? &lt;strong&gt;An institutional mutual fund is the lowest cost fund that one can purchase from a carrier.&lt;/strong&gt; It also has no revenue sharing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A retail mutual fund has higher fees. These fees compensate your broker advisor and also may cover other revenue sharing expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The judge in Tibble v. Edison ultimately determined that the trustees failed their duty of loyalty and prudence. The employer in Tibble v. Edison used retail mutual funds with revenue sharing, resulting in more expensive funds for the employees  According to the judge, &lt;strong&gt;they were accountable to either know or ask if there was a cheaper share class they could have purchased&lt;/strong&gt;and provided to their employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As a sponsor, you’ve got a duty of prudence and loyalty to your participants.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/are-you-truly-fulfilling-your-duties-as-a-retirement-plan-sponsor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“As a sponsor, you’ve got a duty of prudence and loyalty to your participants.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The employer very well could have used institutional funds that were less expensive and lacked revenue sharing. In the end, the employer ended up having to pay dearly for failing in their duty of prudence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a plan sponsor it’s important that you understand all the fees in your plan, so that you can make prudent decisions in the best interests of your employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn more about safeguarding your retirement plan, &lt;strong&gt;p&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ick up a free copy of my book “Save America, Save! The Secrets of a Successful Retirement Plan.”&lt;/strong&gt; You can get your copy at &lt;a href=&quot;www.EpsteinFinancial.com&quot;&gt;www.EpsteinFinancial.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you’re interested in having us evaluate your plan for you, we’d be happy to do a free consultation. Reach out to Matt Gilmore from my office by email at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#109;&amp;#103;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#109;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#101;&amp;#112;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#101;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#102;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt; mgilmore@epsteinfs.com&lt;/a&gt; or by phone at (413) 539-2379.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/are-you-truly-fulfilling-your-duties-as-a-retirement-plan-sponsor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/are-you-truly-fulfilling-your-duties-as-a-retirement-plan-sponsor.html</guid>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Get Sued—Know Your Revenue Sharing Fees</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qz9emGeZkHw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you didn’t know, revenue sharing has been the basis for the largest litigation and lawsuits by the largest law firms across America against you—the planned sponsor fiduciary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lawsuits happen because these law firms claim you don’t understand all the fees in your retirement plan, how those fees are paid, who they’re being paid to, and whether or not they’re reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the video above, I’ve added a slide of a revenue sharing dial which breaks down all the fees and expenses that could be paid inside your retirement plan so you can follow along as I explain each portion. When I show a planned sponsor this dial, 80% of the time, they tell me it’s the first time they’ve ever seen the chart. In fact, we recently took over a $10 million retirement plan from a planned sponsor who told us he’d been asking his broker for years who was getting paid and how they were getting paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So how are revenue sharing fees paid in your retirement plan? I’ll give you an example.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can help you protect yourself against a fiduciary liability lawsuit.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/dont-get-suedknow-your-revenue-sharing-fees.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“We can help you protect yourself against a fiduciary liability lawsuit.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s imagine you have a mutual fund in your retirement plan and the expense ratio is 1%. Of that 1%, let’s assume 0.5% (or 50 basis points) goes to your mutual fund manager as a managing investment fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where does the other half go? Well, 0.25% of it goes toward the 12b-1 fee, which is the commission paid to your broker and what you use to pay for marketing by that mutual fund company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the remaining 0.25%, about 0.2% goes toward shareholder servicing fees—that’s revenue sharing. That’s what the fund company is paying your record keeper to get on the platform and have access to your employees. In other words, it’s a slotting fee. A lot of the litigation I spoke of involves the lawyers arguing that this 20% is really your employees’ money and should be paid back to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining 0.05% goes toward sub-transfer agent fees. These are paid to the company that tracks the money your employees move from fund to fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a plan where the average fund expense is 1.25%, you have another 0.25% (or 25 basis points) that goes toward your asset fee. This is your record keeper basically saying they’re not making enough money to operate your plan, so they have to charge you another 25%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a planned sponsor fiduciary, there are certain questions you must ask yourself. Are those fees reasonable? Can you reduce those fees? If so, how?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can help you with those questions by offering our B-1 Vendor Benchmarking service free of charge.&lt;/strong&gt;All you have to do is give Matt Gilmore, one of our planning consultants, a call at (413) 539-2379. He’ll help you uncover all the fees in your plan and protect you from a fiduciary liability lawsuit by benchmarking those fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about revenue sharing or creating a paycheck for life, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/dont-get-suedknow-your-revenue-sharing-fees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/dont-get-suedknow-your-revenue-sharing-fees.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>1 Simple Way You Can Improve Investment Outcomes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y7Nb2h-ovgM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today I want to focus on what your employees can do to improve their investment outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say upfront, there’s no guarantee when it comes to investing, but there are things employees can do to enhance or improve their potential outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of them is something called automatic rebalancing. This is a feature that just about every record-keeping platform can provide for you.  Automatic rebalancing allows your employees investment options to be automatically rebalanced over long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me give you an example: I pulled &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Charlie+Epstein/Screen+Shots/2017-09-15.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a chart&lt;/a&gt; from page 98 of my book “Paychecks for Life: How to Turn Your 401(k) Into a Paycheck Manufacturing Company,” and the data from this chart comes from my dear friend Professor Craig Israelsen— the author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.7twelveportfolio.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“7Twelve Portfolio.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did Craig and his students uncover in this analysis? They went back over a 40-year period, and they compared investments in a portfolio that has seven different asset classes: large-cap stocks, mid-caps, small-caps, international equities, bonds, cash, commodities, and real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They asked themselves, “What would happen if you invested over a 10, 20, 30, or 40-year period.  Investors who just held onto those investments and did not equally rebalance their investment options, as opposed to investors who had the same investments and annually rebalanced their investment options to maintain their one-seventh investment in each asset class?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are things your employees can do to improve or enhance the potential of investment outcomes%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/1-simple-way-you-can-improve-investment-outcomes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“There are things your employees can do to improve or enhance the potential of investment outcomes”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the results: over a 10-year period of time, the results were still beneficial. From the period between the years 2000 to 2009, during which we had the technology bubble (and the market dropped almost 48%), if they had just held onto those investments, they would have had a 405% gain, which is nothing to be ashamed of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somebody who took the time to rebalance their account once a year, every year, for 40 years, would have seen a gain of 532%. That’s an outperformance of almost 127%, or a 31.4% rebalancing advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s the problem: human nature. Employees simply won’t remember to rebalance their investment accounts. The beauty of automating the annual rebalancing is that all an employee has to do is go online to your record-keeping platform, request that they want their accounts rebalanced monthly, bi-annually or as many times a year as they’d like, and it will be done for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are huge incremental successes that your employees can have, but the question is whether you’re communicating this information to them. If you’re not, we’d like to be of help to you, so go ahead and give us a call or email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/1-simple-way-you-can-improve-investment-outcomes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/1-simple-way-you-can-improve-investment-outcomes.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Can Help You Reduce Your Fiduciary Liability</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qhcyheLO9CA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What impact can fees have on your employees’ success in retirement?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, no one wants to pay more than they have to. &lt;strong&gt;However, when you are the fiduciary of a 401(k) plan, you have a duty of loyalty and prudence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, you have personal liability relating to the results of an employee’s participation in your retirement plan. Therefore, it’s critical that you are benchmarking your plan’s fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, though, I’d like to highlight how you can improve your plans by reducing fees or enhancing investment performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we take a look at the chart featured in the video, we can see that if you are able to reduce an individual’s fees by 1.5% it can make a difference of nearly $120,000 more in a 30-year period.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our goals are to impact fees, impact performance, and reduce your fiduciary liability.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/we-can-help-you-reduce-your-fiduciary-liability.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“Our goals are to impact fees, impact performance, and reduce your fiduciary liability.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By reducing fees and expenses and improving performance to save an employee 1.5%, someone who may otherwise have started with $374,532 when they retire at 65 could instead start retirement with a balance of $498,395.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a difference of more than $1,100 in the money they would be receiving each month.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine how this would impact your employees’ quality of life. That’s what Epstein Financial Services is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our mission and our goals are to impact fees, impact performance, and reduce your fiduciary liability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/we-can-help-you-reduce-your-fiduciary-liability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/we-can-help-you-reduce-your-fiduciary-liability.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Right Way to Give Investment Options to Your Employees</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vqbZQuS2FTM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you provide a diversified investment lineup to your employees that meets your fiduciary obligations as a plan sponsor fiduciary? There are a couple things to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is choice. &lt;strong&gt;Giving your employees too many choices has a negative impact.&lt;/strong&gt; We often evaluate retirement plans and find people that have as many as 100 investment choices. Studies have shown that the more choices you give someone, the less apt they are to take action. More choice does not incentivize people to take action. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A reasonable number of investment options in a 401(k) plan lineup should be about 16 to 18 choices.&lt;/strong&gt; In the video above, I’ve listed all the major investment asset classes in a retirement plan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should have a diversified investment choice for employees who do not want to make an investment choice. In my book “Paychecks for Life,” we found that 85% of your employees would prefer you to make an investment choice for them. This can either be a balance fund, a target life fund, or a lifestyle fund, and it would cover that group of employees. For the other 15% who want to make an investment choice for themselves, it’s critical that you offer them at least one choice in each asset class. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=More choice does not incentivize people to take action.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-right-way-to-give-investment-options-to-your-employees.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“More choice does not incentivize people to take action.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as active funds versus passive funds, you have a duty of prudence and a duty of loyalty to your employees. This means you should offer them choice, but you shouldn’t make the choice for them so you’re not liable for their investment decisions. In order to do that, &lt;strong&gt;you should offer both passive (index) funds and actively managed funds. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should have an index fund in each of the blend categories of the asset classes, including “Growth,” “Mid-cap,” and “Small-cap.” This will be low-cost investing—anywhere from six to eight basis points. On the outside, meaning large-cap growth, large-cap value, mid-cap growth, mid-cap value, small-cap growth, and small-cap value, you should have an active fund option. In the “International” category, offer an index fund and an active fund. In the “Bond” category, offer the same thing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do this, you’ll end up with about 16 to 18 choices, which is all your employees need to build a robust, diversified investment choice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about offering investment options to your employees, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-right-way-to-give-investment-options-to-your-employees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-right-way-to-give-investment-options-to-your-employees.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using a Benchmark to Track Fiduciary Fees</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aKZ8tmdG0Zg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this installment in my series—based on my book, “Save America, Save!”—we’re talking about getting a benchmark analysis. One of the keys to being a great plan sponsor fiduciary is ensuring that the fees that you pay in your plan are reasonable. Who and how do you define “reasonable?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under ERISA, the only way you know if your fees are reasonable is to benchmark them against other expenses. So, you’ve got a record keeper, you might have a third-party administrator, and you’ve got an advisor. These are the people you are paying for their services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to understand who the providers are and what services are they providing, and what are the fees that they are charging for those services? Who’s acting as a fiduciary and is there a conflict of interest?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So the best way to determine if the fees those individuals are charging are reasonable is to benchmark against other plans,&lt;/strong&gt;other record keepers, and other advisors. This can be complicated because you need accurate data from the others in order for this to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need accurate data to create a solid benchmark.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/using-a-benchmark-to-track-fiduciary-fees.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“You need accurate data to create a solid benchmark.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Epstein Financial Services, we have a very simple vendor benchmark of services that we want to offer to you free of charge that will help you determine if your fees are reasonable. What we do is we look at a universe of retirement plans that have similar characteristics to yours— plan size, number of employees and investments, and any other data. We then reach out across the country and pull data from other plans in order to create a benchmark for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to learn more about getting your own free benchmark or you have any other retirement questions, please call us or shoot us an email. We’d be happy to help!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/using-a-benchmark-to-track-fiduciary-fees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/using-a-benchmark-to-track-fiduciary-fees.html</guid>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Bulletproof Yourself From Fiduciary Liability</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y8zeNay8YUc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.scheduleonce.com/Consultation-EpsteinFinancial&quot;&gt;Schedule a Consultation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epsteinfinancial.com/free-book-offer.html&quot;&gt;Click here to get your free book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that you can design a retirement plan that can nearly bulletproof you from any fiduciary liability. You do this by hiring prudent experts; people who have a &lt;strong&gt;3(38) ;3(21) ;or 3(16); designation. &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;Someone with a 338 designation has discretionary authority over the plan’s investments. You can hire a prudent expert with this designation to make decisions about which investments you should have in your plan. 
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;A 321 fiduciary provides you with data and information so that you as the plan sponsor fiduciary can choose which investment choices to have in your investment plan.
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;A 316 fiduciary takes on all the liability of administering your plan, and this is a critical role that most plan sponsors don’t take advantage of. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can help you create a shield that virtually bulletproofs you from fiduciary responsibility.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/how-to-bulletproof-yourself-from-fiduciary-liability.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“We can help you create a shield that virtually bulletproofs you from fiduciary responsibility.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;Think about it—you’re a busy HR director trying to deal with payroll and the responsibilities of your employees, and now you have the burden of making sure all the notices go out on time and everybody is being communicated with. If these things don’t happen, then you can be liable for it.
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our team can help you design a retirement plan with a fiduciary shield&lt;/strong&gt; around it that could bulletproof you as a plan sponsor fiduciary by allowing other individuals to be that 3(38); 3(21); or 3(16); and reduce your fiduciary liability. It’s not that difficult, but it’s important to know what your options are.
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;If you want to learn more about creating a successful retirement plan, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/how-to-bulletproof-yourself-from-fiduciary-liability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/how-to-bulletproof-yourself-from-fiduciary-liability.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does The Current Bull Market Have Many Years Left?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oGKb6Bmg2Ls&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently rejoined Liz Claman on Fox Business’s show “Countdown to the Closing Bell” to share my thoughts on the secular bull market and give a couple of stock picks. &lt;strong&gt;Here’s a quick summary of what I talked about.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current bull market is in its 9th year and that makes some investors nervous. I predict it has &lt;strong&gt;16 more years&lt;/strong&gt;! Secular markets can go for 21 years on average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My stock picks are… Illumina Inc. and Twitter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To catch my full appearance, just click play on the video above. Thank you for watching.  Let me know your views on this topic.  Just send me your email at cdepstein@the401kcoach.com. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/does-the-current-bull-market-have-many-years-left.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/does-the-current-bull-market-have-many-years-left.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outsourcing Plan Sponsor Obligations</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tiaASuGRTXw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.scheduleonce.com/Consultation-EpsteinFinancial&quot;&gt;Schedule a Consultation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epsteinfinancial.com/free-book-offer.html&quot;&gt;Click here to get your free book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your role and responsibility as a fiduciary of a retirement plan is an important aspect of a 401(k) plan.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;ERISA—the rules and regulations that govern how a retirement plan is established and the process you need to have as a plan sponsor—was established in 1974. There’s a very important section that many people overlook, the Exclusive Purpose Rule. It states that when you establish a retirement plan, you’re doing it for the exclusive purpose of providing benefits to your employees and their beneficiaries.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;We believe that it’s the basis to operate from to determine you’re doing everything you should be doing as a plan sponsor fiduciary to meet the obligation of helping your employees create that kind of benefit.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;As a plan sponsor fiduciary, you have a duty of loyalty and a duty of prudence to your employees. This is the highest standard you can have in the industry. Being loyal to your employees means doing everything for their and their beneficiaries’ benefit and not doing anything that would harm them, disservice them, or disrupt them from creating benefits. Being prudent means doing everything with a standard and the knowledge and ability to run that plan would have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can help you design a retirement plan with a fiduciary shield that can bulletproof you as the plan sponsor.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/outsourcing-plan-sponsor-obligations.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“We can help you design a retirement plan with a fiduciary shield that can bulletproof you as the plan sponsor.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem as a plan sponsor is that it’s not your full-time job or specialty.&lt;/strong&gt; The government understands that, so you can outsource these roles. Frankly, we believe you can design a retirement plan that will almost bulletproof you from any fiduciary liability.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;You do this by hiring prudent experts, or those with a 338, 321, or 316 designations.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;A 338 has discretionary authority over the plan’s advancements, and you can hire one to make decisions about investment choices in your plan. A 321 fiduciary provides you with data and information so that you as the plan sponsor can choose which investments to have in your plan. A 316 fiduciary takes on all the liability of administering your plan, a critical role that most plan sponsors don’t take advantage of.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Think about it—you’re a busy HR director who now has the burden of making sure all notices are going out on time and that everyone is being communicated with, and if these things don’t happen, then you could be liable.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;We can help you design a retirement plan with a fiduciary shield that can bulletproof you as plan sponsor by letting you allow other individuals to be a 338, a 321, and/or 316. It’s not difficult, but it’s important to be aware of your options.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to give me a call. I’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/outsourcing-plan-sponsor-obligations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/outsourcing-plan-sponsor-obligations.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Stretch Match and Courageous 401(k) Plan Design</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3ChQUrtOJ4I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://secure.scheduleonce.com/Consultation-EpsteinFinancial&quot;&gt;Schedule a Consultation&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epsteinfinancial.com/free-book-offer.html&quot;&gt;Click here to get your free book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to my series on how to create a successful retirement plan for your employees. In the last few videos, I’ve been talking about the various options you have for automating your employee’s savings to create paychecks for life. However, I want to switch gears today and talk about another important topic. I’m talking about the stretch match and courageous plan design. 
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The courageous plan design requires a real commitment on your part as a plan sponsor to do more than just offer investment choices and a reasonable fee.&lt;/strong&gt; The truth is that if your employees aren’t incentivized to save more, they won’t save more. What you really have to do is change their mindset by incentivizing them to save more money, otherwise they won’t save enough. Enough is around 10% per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With this strategy, employees will need to save 10% to get the full match.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-stretch-match-and-courageous-401k-plan-design.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“With this strategy, employees will need to save 10% to get the full match.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;On a retirement plan that matches 50 cents on the dollar up to 6%, we’ve found that employees only end up saving 6%, not that 10% that they need. The reason they have for not saving more is that their contributions aren’t being matched, so what’s the point? That’s just their initial mindset.
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;If you changed your plan design from contributing 50 cents on the dollar up to 6% to 50 cents on the dollar up to 2%, and then 25% on the dollar all the way up to 8%, &lt;strong&gt;your employees would have to save all the way up to 10% to get the entire 3% match. &lt;/strong&gt;With this strategy, you’re stretching your matching dollars while also incentivizing your employees to save the 10% they will need to in order to create paychecks for life. The great part about it is that it doesn’t cost you any more money.
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;This is a strategy that works and creates a win-win situation for you and your employees. In my next installment, I’m going to talk about the safe harbor plan designs. There are three of them and each is critical in showing how you as an owner and your highly compensated employees can save the maximum amount allowable by the government.
&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;If you have any questions or feedback for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-stretch-match-and-courageous-401k-plan-design.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-stretch-match-and-courageous-401k-plan-design.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
