<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epstein Financial Video Blog</title>
    <description>We create greater clarity, confidence and the capabilities for entrepreneurs, medical practitioners, 401k participants and retirees to maximize the power of their financial future. Our goal is to help you generate a &quot;paycheck for life&quot; to pay for all the things you desire to do and to live a fulfilling and engaged life.</description>
    <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 16:34:53 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 16:34:53 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Retirement Planning Tool Will Help Your Employees Exponentially</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/usTdekBhGuk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re going to focus on what I call “the Gap Statement.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, we’ve been talking a lot about employee engagement. If you aren’t taking advantage of the Retirement Gap Analysis Report, though, &lt;strong&gt;you aren’t helping your employees to the fullest extent.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This report specifically tells your employees what they need to save for retirement based on their needs-based rate of return, which is the least amount of risk they need to take in order to achieve a near-guaranteed paycheck for the rest of their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words: What is the return your employees need to earn with the least amount of risk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the Gap Statement will show your employees how much of a monthly income they’re going to have when they reach their retirement years. It’ll take into account a number of things, and will &lt;strong&gt;then show them the gap between their current monthly income and what they need to live on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Gap Statement will show your employees how much of a monthly income they’re going to have when they reach their retirement years.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/this-retirement-planning-tool-will-help-your-employees-exponentially.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“The Gap Statement will show your employees how much of a monthly income they’re going to have when they reach their retirement years.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will also show how much more monthly income employees can have if they gradually increase their savings rate. This monthly income has a lot to do with something called the income replacement ratio which I will discuss further in a future video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This report will not only tell employees how much they’ll be saving toward retirement, but also how much they’ll save in terms of taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultimately, the net cost for them to increase their contributions may not be as much as they think.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Charlie+Epstein/GAP.pdf&quot;&gt;For a free copy of the Gap Analysis, click here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/this-retirement-planning-tool-will-help-your-employees-exponentially.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/this-retirement-planning-tool-will-help-your-employees-exponentially.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do Your Employees Have a Realistic Understanding of Their Own Retirement Plan?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IYidOjxvSwE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I want to focus on something I call “needs-based versus greeds-based” rate of return. Before getting into the details of this and why it’s so important, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epsteinfinancial.com/free-book-offer.html&quot;&gt;I want to make sure that you have an opportunity to get my book “Save America, Save!: The Secrets of a Successful Retirement Plan.”&lt;/a&gt; It’s chock-full of all of my secrets on how to turn your 401(k) into a successful retirement plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are passionate about teaching employees how to create a paycheck for life and how to turn their 401(k) into a paycheck manufacturing company. But if I asked your employees how much they want to earn on the money they’re contributing to their retirement plan, do you know what they’d say to me? They’d say 10%, or even up to 50%!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, &lt;strong&gt;your employees’ greeds-based rate of return is an unrealistic number.&lt;/strong&gt; They actually believe that they’re going to get a 10 to 50% rate of return on their investment, year-in and year-out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been in a nine-year bull market. There are employees in their 20’s who have been contributing to their retirement plan that have never experienced a bear market, which is a drop of 20% more in their account value. &lt;strong&gt;This is critical&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s also what I think makes the 401(k) plan America’s largest casino, because people are rolling the dice when it comes to their 401(k) plan’s rate of return. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if I were to ask your employees, “Can you tell me what your needs-based rate of return is?”, the answer I’d get would be open-mouthed silence. &lt;strong&gt;They don’t know what that is.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The needs-based rate of return is the single most important rate of return.&lt;/strong&gt;  My own definition of what constitutes “needs-based” is what rate of return employees need to earn on their money, year-in and year-out, with the least amount of risk that will almost guarantee that they’ll have a paycheck for the rest of their life.  It is critical that your employees calculate their needs-based rate of return today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=In general, the needs-based rate of return that most people will have will be between 4% and 6%%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/do-your-employees-have-a-realistic-understanding-of-their-own-retirement-plan.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“In general, the needs-based rate of return that most people will have will be between 4% and 6%”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since your employees don’t know what their needs-based rate of return is, &lt;strong&gt;we have a calculator available called the Desirement Mortgage Calculator&lt;/strong&gt;. In my first book, “Paychecks For Life: How to Turn Your 401(k) Into a Paycheck Manufacturing Company,” I go into more detail about the Desirement Mortgage Calculator, which I will send to you by clicking the above link for a &lt;em&gt;free copy. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for my next blog, where I talk about what I call a GAP Statement and how we show your employees how to project their investments and savings returns, how to identify their needs-based rate of return, and how to create that paycheck for life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this or other topics, feel free to give me a call or send an email. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/do-your-employees-have-a-realistic-understanding-of-their-own-retirement-plan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/do-your-employees-have-a-realistic-understanding-of-their-own-retirement-plan.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The First Steps to Creating Paychecks for Life</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/O5xD6sc0CRk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m going to give you, the plan sponsor, the secret to turning your company’s 401(k) plan into a paycheck manufacturing company for you and your employees. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a plan sponsor, suppose you have a retirement plan that has no fees for investments, services, or administration.  Let’s also suppose that this plan has the best scoring investment options possible.  Some people would say that is the definition of a successful retirement plan. I would argue that and say that there is one key element missing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What’s missing?&lt;strong&gt; Employee engagement!&lt;/strong&gt; Are your employees contributing to the plan? Are they contributing enough money to maximize their retirement plan to create a paycheck for life?  You can offer the best plan imaginable, but if your employees are not engaged and contributing, it will not be a successful retirement plan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The perfect plan requires employee participation.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-first-steps-to-creating-paychecks-for-life.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“The perfect plan requires employee participation.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Before 1974, retirement income was from a pension plan. Employees knew if they worked for the company for 30 years, they’d have a pension plan that would generate an income for the rest of their life.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pension plans don’t exist anymore.  Today your employees must contribute to their retirement plans. If they’re not properly allocating their money in the right investments, and if they’re not adjusting their investments over time, how can they possibly create that paycheck for life?  &lt;strong&gt;This is where employee engagement is so critical. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;ERISA is the law that established the retirement plan industry in 1974.  ERISA’s most important rule is something called the “exclusive purpose rule” which states that if you’re a plan sponsor and you establish a retirement plan for the benefit of your participants, you’re doing it for the exclusive purpose of providing benefits to them and their beneficiaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next series of vlogs will focus on how your company can help your employees become more engaged and excited to contribute to their 401(k) to maximize their contributions toward their retirement plan to create that paycheck for life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-first-steps-to-creating-paychecks-for-life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-first-steps-to-creating-paychecks-for-life.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Share Classes to Retirement Plan Sponsors</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sKjO6rdQqxA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my last few videos, I’ve been talking about things like revenue sharing and expenses. Today, I’d like to dive a little bit deeper into this topic by talking about share classes. &lt;strong&gt;We’ll focus on the different kinds of share classes that mutual fund companies have, why they have them, and what you need to be aware of as a plan sponsor to avoid a potential lawsuit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Even if you don’t have a huge retirement plan with $3 billion in assets, you need to behave with a duty of prudence and loyalty as if you do. On page 72 of my book, “Save America, Save: The Secrets to a Successful 401(k) Plan,” there’s a little chart titled “Share Class Matters” that I want you to look at. &lt;strong&gt;You can see it in the video above.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this case, you see three share classes: R3, R4, and R6. When you establish a retirement plan, you must decide how you’re going to pay the expenses involved with the plan. The R3 share class has an expense ratio of 1.14%. This means that the fund’s performance is reduced by 1.14% to pay for the expenses in the plan. There are also revenue sharing numbers that need to be considered. In the R3 share class, there are 65 basis points of revenue sharing, which are used to pay your broker and record keeper. With this share class, you are basically saying that you don’t want to pick up any expenses and your employees can pay for them out of revenue sharing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;With an R4 share class, you have 85 basis points, but only 35 of them are for revenue sharing. &lt;strong&gt;With this class, you will use those basis points to pay for the record keeper, but not the broker or advisor. You can deduct this expense on your taxes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You need to behave with a duty of prudence and loyalty.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-importance-of-share-classes-to-retirement-plan-sponsors.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“You need to behave with a duty of prudence and loyalty.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have the R6 share class. The expense ratio is at 0.5% and there is no revenue sharing. By using this share class, you are saying that you only want your employees to have to pay the cost of the mutual fund expense. This means that you’ll have to pay those other expenses. One solution for this would be to add in an “asset fee” or a “wrap fee,” which is far more prudent and equitable for you to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The way we would design your retirement plan is by taking the lowest share class and sharing the cost of adding basis points between your employees equally, regardless of the fund they pick. &lt;/strong&gt;That’s how you establish a retirement plan that will meet your obligation of prudence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. Also, if you’d like a free copy of my book, head on over to my website and request your copy. I look forward to hearing from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-importance-of-share-classes-to-retirement-plan-sponsors.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-importance-of-share-classes-to-retirement-plan-sponsors.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Know What Your Hard and Soft Dollar Fees Are?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xiDhK6UhnP8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in my &lt;a href=&quot;/are-you-truly-fulfilling-your-duties-as-a-retirement-plan-sponsor.html&quot;&gt;last video&lt;/a&gt;, the recent court case of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tibble v. Edison&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is something, that you as a plan sponsor fiduciary, need to understand because it pertains to the fees and expenses in your plan and what types of share class or mutual funds you have in that plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a plan sponsor fiduciary, you have a duty of prudence and a duty of loyalty. You need to be loyal to your employees and make sure you do everything in their best interests. To do that,&lt;strong&gt; you need to have a process for monitoring the investments in your retirement plan and being prudent about that process.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I want to cover the fees and expenses in a retirement plan, primarily the hard dollar and soft dollar costs. You need to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who your service providers are.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What services they provide .  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What services they provide.                  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the fees they charge for their services (they can be both hard and soft dollar fees).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether the fees are reasonable.                 &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who’ acting as a fiduciary to your plan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whether anyone has a conflict of interest in that process.               &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On page 66 and 67 in my book “Save America, Save!” I lay out what the hard dollar and soft dollar fees are in a retirement plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s important that you as a plan sponsor fiduciary understand all the fees in your retirement plan.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/do-you-know-what-your-hard-and-soft-dollar-fees-are.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“It’s important that you as a plan sponsor fiduciary understand all the fees in your retirement plan.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard dollar fees are typically fees you pay directly to your service providers.  &lt;/strong&gt;You could write a check to your third-party administrator (if you have one) and pay them an annual administration fee and maybe a participation fee for each person in the plan. You might write a check directly to your advisor, which you could deduct out of your corporation. You could also write a check to your record keeper. All of these hard dollar fees come out of the company’s pocket rather than the participant accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most plan sponsors may have all of those fees bundled and coming out of the mutual funds in the plan, or what’s known as a soft dollar fee. &lt;strong&gt;Soft dollar fees are when you pay your service providers indirectly from your mutual fund.&lt;/strong&gt; This is where you can get into trouble, though, because soft dollar fees are a slippery slope and the reason why &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tibble v. Edison&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; ended up as a lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, it’s important that you as a plan sponsor fiduciary understand all the fees in your retirement plan—both hard and soft—so you can make prudent decisions as to what’s in the best interests of your employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my next video, I’ll delve into the variety of share classes you can choose from. In the meantime, if you have any questions about this topic or would like a free consultation for your investment plan, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/do-you-know-what-your-hard-and-soft-dollar-fees-are.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/do-you-know-what-your-hard-and-soft-dollar-fees-are.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Are You Truly Fulfilling Your Duties as a Retirement Plan Sponsor?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/I9Pi9Dx-Klo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of activity right now in the 401(k) industry, but today I want to talk specifically about a court case that has been dragging out for the past six or seven years: &lt;em&gt;Tibble v. Edison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this case, the Judge finally ruled that if you have a 401(k) plan, you’ve got a duty of prudence and loyalty to your participants. You must monitor your plans investments. With the correct process in place, you should be able to prudently choose investments for your plan.  &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;In this case, which was a $3 billion plan, the sponsors’ fiduciaries had both institutional share mutual funds and retail share mutual funds.&lt;br /&gt;But what’s the difference between these? &lt;strong&gt;An institutional mutual fund is the lowest cost fund that one can purchase from a carrier.&lt;/strong&gt; It also has no revenue sharing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A retail mutual fund has higher fees.&lt;/strong&gt; These fees compensate your broker/advisor and also may cover other plan related expenses.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The Judge in &lt;em&gt;Tibble v. Edison&lt;/em&gt; ultimately determined that the trustees failed their duty of loyalty and prudence. The employer in &lt;em&gt;Tibble v. Edison&lt;/em&gt; used retail mutual funds with revenue sharing, resulting in more expensive funds for the employees.  According to the Judge, &lt;strong&gt;the Plan Fiduciaries should have known if there was a cheaper share class they could have purchased and provided to their employees.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=As a sponsor, you’ve got a duty of prudence and loyalty to your participants.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/are-you-truly-fulfilling-your-duties-as-a-retirement-plan-sponsor.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“As a sponsor, you’ve got a duty of prudence and loyalty to your participants.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The employer could have used institutional funds that were less expensive and without revenue sharing. In the end, the employer ended up with significant penalties for failing in their duty of prudence.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As a plan sponsor it’s important that you understand all the fees in your plan so that you can make prudent decisions in the best interests of your employees.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you’d like to learn more about safeguarding your retirement plan, &lt;strong&gt;pick up a free copy of my book, “Save America, Save! The Secrets of a Successful 401(k) Plan.”&lt;/strong&gt; You can get your copy at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epsteinfinancial.com/home.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;www.EpsteinFinancial.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Also, if you’re interested in having us evaluate your plan for you, we’d be happy to do a free consultation. Reach out to Krista Krupa from my office by email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kkrupa@epsteinfs.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;kkrupa@epsteinfs.com&lt;/a&gt;
 or by phone at (413) 539-2371.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/are-you-truly-fulfilling-your-duties-as-a-retirement-plan-sponsor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/are-you-truly-fulfilling-your-duties-as-a-retirement-plan-sponsor.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Get Sued—Know Your Revenue Sharing Fees</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qz9emGeZkHw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you didn’t know, revenue sharing has been the basis for the largest litigation and lawsuits by the largest law firms across America against you—the planned sponsor fiduciary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lawsuits happen because these law firms claim you don’t understand all the fees in your retirement plan, how those fees are paid, who they’re being paid to, and whether or not they’re reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the video above, I’ve added a slide of a revenue sharing dial which breaks down all the fees and expenses that could be paid inside your retirement plan so you can follow along as I explain each portion. When I show a planned sponsor this dial, 80% of the time, they tell me it’s the first time they’ve ever seen the chart. In fact, we recently took over a $10 million retirement plan from a planned sponsor who told us he’d been asking his broker for years who was getting paid and how they were getting paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So how are revenue sharing fees paid in your retirement plan? I’ll give you an example.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can help you protect yourself against a fiduciary liability lawsuit.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/dont-get-suedknow-your-revenue-sharing-fees.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“We can help you protect yourself against a fiduciary liability lawsuit.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s imagine you have a mutual fund in your retirement plan and the expense ratio is 1%. Of that 1%, let’s assume 0.5% (or 50 basis points) goes to your mutual fund manager as a managing investment fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where does the other half go? Well, 0.25% of it goes toward the 12b-1 fee, which is the commission paid to your broker and what you use to pay for marketing by that mutual fund company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the remaining 0.25%, about 0.2% goes toward shareholder servicing fees—that’s revenue sharing. That’s what the fund company is paying your record keeper to get on the platform and have access to your employees. In other words, it’s a slotting fee. A lot of the litigation I spoke of involves the lawyers arguing that this 20% is really your employees’ money and should be paid back to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining 0.05% goes toward sub-transfer agent fees. These are paid to the company that tracks the money your employees move from fund to fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a plan where the average fund expense is 1.25%, you have another 0.25% (or 25 basis points) that goes toward your asset fee. This is your record keeper basically saying they’re not making enough money to operate your plan, so they have to charge you another 25%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a planned sponsor fiduciary, there are certain questions you must ask yourself. Are those fees reasonable? Can you reduce those fees? If so, how?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can help you with those questions by offering our B-1 Vendor Benchmarking service free of charge.&lt;/strong&gt;All you have to do is give Matt Gilmore, one of our planning consultants, a call at (413) 539-2379. He’ll help you uncover all the fees in your plan and protect you from a fiduciary liability lawsuit by benchmarking those fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about revenue sharing or creating a paycheck for life, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/dont-get-suedknow-your-revenue-sharing-fees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/dont-get-suedknow-your-revenue-sharing-fees.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>1 Simple Way You Can Improve Investment Outcomes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y7Nb2h-ovgM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today I want to focus on what your employees can do to improve their investment outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to say upfront, there’s no guarantee when it comes to investing, but there are things employees can do to enhance or improve their potential outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of them is something called automatic rebalancing. This is a feature that just about every record-keeping platform can provide for you.  Automatic rebalancing allows your employees investment options to be automatically rebalanced over long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me give you an example: I pulled &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Charlie+Epstein/Screen+Shots/2017-09-15.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a chart&lt;/a&gt; from page 98 of my book “Paychecks for Life: How to Turn Your 401(k) Into a Paycheck Manufacturing Company,” and the data from this chart comes from my dear friend Professor Craig Israelsen— the author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.7twelveportfolio.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“7Twelve Portfolio.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did Craig and his students uncover in this analysis? They went back over a 40-year period, and they compared investments in a portfolio that has seven different asset classes: large-cap stocks, mid-caps, small-caps, international equities, bonds, cash, commodities, and real estate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They asked themselves, “What would happen if you invested over a 10, 20, 30, or 40-year period.  Investors who just held onto those investments and did not equally rebalance their investment options, as opposed to investors who had the same investments and annually rebalanced their investment options to maintain their one-seventh investment in each asset class?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are things your employees can do to improve or enhance the potential of investment outcomes%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/1-simple-way-you-can-improve-investment-outcomes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“There are things your employees can do to improve or enhance the potential of investment outcomes”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the results: over a 10-year period of time, the results were still beneficial. From the period between the years 2000 to 2009, during which we had the technology bubble (and the market dropped almost 48%), if they had just held onto those investments, they would have had a 405% gain, which is nothing to be ashamed of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But somebody who took the time to rebalance their account once a year, every year, for 40 years, would have seen a gain of 532%. That’s an outperformance of almost 127%, or a 31.4% rebalancing advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s the problem: human nature. Employees simply won’t remember to rebalance their investment accounts. The beauty of automating the annual rebalancing is that all an employee has to do is go online to your record-keeping platform, request that they want their accounts rebalanced monthly, bi-annually or as many times a year as they’d like, and it will be done for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are huge incremental successes that your employees can have, but the question is whether you’re communicating this information to them. If you’re not, we’d like to be of help to you, so go ahead and give us a call or email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/1-simple-way-you-can-improve-investment-outcomes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/1-simple-way-you-can-improve-investment-outcomes.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>We Can Help You Reduce Your Fiduciary Liability</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qhcyheLO9CA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What impact can fees have on your employees’ success in retirement?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, no one wants to pay more than they have to. &lt;strong&gt;However, when you are the fiduciary of a 401(k) plan, you have a duty of loyalty and prudence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, you have personal liability relating to the results of an employee’s participation in your retirement plan. Therefore, it’s critical that you are benchmarking your plan’s fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, though, I’d like to highlight how you can improve your plans by reducing fees or enhancing investment performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we take a look at the chart featured in the video, we can see that if you are able to reduce an individual’s fees by 1.5% it can make a difference of nearly $120,000 more in a 30-year period.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our goals are to impact fees, impact performance, and reduce your fiduciary liability.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/we-can-help-you-reduce-your-fiduciary-liability.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“Our goals are to impact fees, impact performance, and reduce your fiduciary liability.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By reducing fees and expenses and improving performance to save an employee 1.5%, someone who may otherwise have started with $374,532 when they retire at 65 could instead start retirement with a balance of $498,395.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a difference of more than $1,100 in the money they would be receiving each month.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine how this would impact your employees’ quality of life. That’s what Epstein Financial Services is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our mission and our goals are to impact fees, impact performance, and reduce your fiduciary liability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/we-can-help-you-reduce-your-fiduciary-liability.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/we-can-help-you-reduce-your-fiduciary-liability.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Right Way to Give Investment Options to Your Employees</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vqbZQuS2FTM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you provide a diversified investment lineup to your employees that meets your fiduciary obligations as a plan sponsor fiduciary? There are a couple things to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is choice. &lt;strong&gt;Giving your employees too many choices has a negative impact.&lt;/strong&gt; We often evaluate retirement plans and find people that have as many as 100 investment choices. Studies have shown that the more choices you give someone, the less apt they are to take action. More choice does not incentivize people to take action. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A reasonable number of investment options in a 401(k) plan lineup should be about 16 to 18 choices.&lt;/strong&gt; In the video above, I’ve listed all the major investment asset classes in a retirement plan. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should have a diversified investment choice for employees who do not want to make an investment choice. In my book “Paychecks for Life,” we found that 85% of your employees would prefer you to make an investment choice for them. This can either be a balance fund, a target life fund, or a lifestyle fund, and it would cover that group of employees. For the other 15% who want to make an investment choice for themselves, it’s critical that you offer them at least one choice in each asset class. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=More choice does not incentivize people to take action.%20http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-right-way-to-give-investment-options-to-your-employees.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“More choice does not incentivize people to take action.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as active funds versus passive funds, you have a duty of prudence and a duty of loyalty to your employees. This means you should offer them choice, but you shouldn’t make the choice for them so you’re not liable for their investment decisions. In order to do that, &lt;strong&gt;you should offer both passive (index) funds and actively managed funds. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should have an index fund in each of the blend categories of the asset classes, including “Growth,” “Mid-cap,” and “Small-cap.” This will be low-cost investing—anywhere from six to eight basis points. On the outside, meaning large-cap growth, large-cap value, mid-cap growth, mid-cap value, small-cap growth, and small-cap value, you should have an active fund option. In the “International” category, offer an index fund and an active fund. In the “Bond” category, offer the same thing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do this, you’ll end up with about 16 to 18 choices, which is all your employees need to build a robust, diversified investment choice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about offering investment options to your employees, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be happy to help.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-right-way-to-give-investment-options-to-your-employees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.epsteinfinancial.com/the-right-way-to-give-investment-options-to-your-employees.html</guid>
        
        <category>401K</category>
        
        <category>Financial Consultant</category>
        
        <category>Retirement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
